<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An ordinance by the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament; for the preservation of the vvesterne parts of the Kingdome. John Brown Cleric. Parliamentorum.</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1642</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82992</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1779</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E83_29</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R22433</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99871749</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99871749</idno>
            <idno type="VID">124165</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82992)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 124165)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 14:E83[29])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An ordinance by the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament; for the preservation of the vvesterne parts of the Kingdome. John Brown Cleric. Parliamentorum.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Parliament.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by R. Ohen and G. Dexter, for Henry Overton, and are to be sold at his shop in Popeshead Alley,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>MDCXLII [1642]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Directions for reimbursing those who contributed money, plate, or horses for the Parliamentary army.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Decemb. 29".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:124165:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:124165:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>AN ORDINANCE BY THE LORDS and COMMONS Aſſembled in PARLIAMENT; For the preſervation of the VVeſterne parts of the KINGDOME.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>John Brown Cleric. Parliamentorum.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed by <hi>R. Ohen</hi> and <hi>G. Dexter,</hi> for <hi>Henry Overton,</hi> and are to be ſold at his Shop in <hi>Popes head Alley.</hi> MDCXLII.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:124165:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:124165:2"/>
            <head>Die Sabbati <hi>24.</hi> Decemb. <hi>1642.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas diverſe perſons well affected to the good and ſafety of this Kingdome, have con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tributed in Money, Plate and Horſe, for ſuppreſſion of the preſent Rebellion, and Inſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection by Papiſts, Delinquents, and other Malignant perſons in the Weſterne parts, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Command of Sir <hi>Ralph Hopton,</hi> and his Adherents Rebells, and Traytors: and for the rrliefe of the good Subjects there. It is there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Ordered, and ordained by the Lords and Commons now aſſembled in <hi>Parliament,</hi> that all and every ſuch Perſon and Perſons, as have alreadie, or ſhall raiſe, either Money, Plate, or Horſe for the ſaid ſervice, ſhall bee ſatisfied and repaide again with in ſix moneths, with in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt for the ſame, out of the firſt moneys that ſhall be levied and raiſed in the Counties of
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:124165:3"/>
               <hi>Cornewell, Devon<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Sommerſet, Dorſet<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> wil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſhire</hi> and <hi>Southampton,</hi> and the Counties and Cities of <hi>Briſtoll,</hi> and <hi>Exon.</hi> and the Towne and County of <hi>Poole,</hi> upon any Order or Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of one, or both Houſes of <hi>Parliament.</hi> Or by any other Levies or Collections, made or to bee made in the ſaid ſeverall and reſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Counties, and Places for that end &amp; pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe; And it is further ordered and ordained, by the Authority aforeſaid, that <hi>Hugh Sow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Young</hi> of the City of <hi>London, Merchants,</hi> ſhall be Treaſurers for the receiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and disburſing of all, and every ſumme or ſummes of money which ſhall be raiſed for the uſe aboveſaid, who are hereby nominated, conſtituted, and appointed Treaſurers, and Receivers as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And it is further ordered and ordained, by the Authority aforeſaid, that the ſaid <hi>Hugh Sowden,</hi> and <hi>Thomas Young,</hi> ſhall and may pay and deliver out of the ſaid Contributions, ſuch moneyes and Horſe to ſuch Perſon, or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, and in ſuch manner, and forme, as the <hi>Committee</hi> of the Lords and Commons for the defence of the Weſterne parts, or any foure or more of them, by any writings under their hands ſhall limitt, appoint, and declare: And that the Warrant or Warrants of the ſaid <hi>Committee,</hi> for the iſſuing our of the ſaid Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neyes, or deliverie of the ſaid Horſes; or of any foure, or more of them, together with
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:124165:3"/>the Acquittance, or the Acquittances Receipt or Receipts in writings, under the hand of the Perſon or Perſons, which ſhall bee appointed as aforeſaid by the ſaid <hi>Committee,</hi> or foure or more of them, ſhall be a ſufficient diſcharge to the Treaſurers or Receivers in this Ordinance named, for ſo much money, or ſuch Horſe or Horſes, as ſhall be comprehended in ſuch Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quittance, or Acquittances, for the iſſuing out, and payment of the ſaid ſumme, or ſummes of money, or delivery of ſuch Horſe and Horſes reſpectively.</p>
            <p>And it is further ordered by the Authoritie aforeſaid, That the Treaſuers and Receivers ſhall not at all pay any ſumme, or ſummes of Money, or deliver, or cauſe to bee delivered any Horſe or Horſes, or Plate to bee by them received upon any other direction, Warrant, or demand whatſoever.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
